In this video, what are we doing? We're doing backward reasoning, okay? So backward reasoning,
so intuitively, backward reasoning doesn't have a logical difference from forward reasoning.
What do I mean by that? At the end of the day, both of them are modus ponens in either you apply it
backwards or forwards. So let me just give you the very intuitive idea behind backwards reasoning,
and then I will show you how to do it in Isabelle, but I don't think you need to write,
like, I don't think you can use it to write pen and paper proofs. So backward reasoning is
the following, okay? So the idea, backwards reasoning. So intuition, and then I will just do an
example. Intuition is if you want to prove p and you know how to prove, sorry, and you already have
proved that, and you already have effect, and you have that, for example, some q, from some q, you
can derive p. Then with backward reasoning, you can change the goal of proving p to q. What does
that mean? If I want to prove p and I know that I always can derive p from q, then if I prove q,
then I know I can derive p from that using this fact. So basically, let's go in Isabelle to show
you how that works. Or maybe let me just try and look at how the goals would evolve here in the
paper. So if you have a goal, so let me just write it down. That is to say, if the goal is p
using q, we can change the goal to q.